POPURI
As all of you are already aware,
this upcoming November 1st
is Tani-kun's birthday!
BOOM
Huh? It's Tani's birthday?
I was not aware.
What should I surprise him with?
Oh, I just don't know!
And don't stand around yakking here.
Has Tani-kun acted like he wanted
anything in particular lately?
I have no clue.
You should ask him that stuff yourself.
Yamada Man, have you
ever gotten any surprises
that made you happy
or made a big impression?
Oh... Hm, I'm sure there were.
What good is it asking Yamada?
They're totally different!
Like an album or something?
Oh! How lovely!
He's got experience?
But, you know...
I don't know anything
about Yamada's love life,
but I feel a huge gap
between us right now.
Taira, how about you?
Huh?
How about you? How about you?
How about you?
For that kind of thing... I don't think
it's about the gift being right or wrong.
It's that someone
remembered your birthday.
Them wanting to celebrate
makes you happy, right?
Not that I care, though.
Stare...
You're so grown-up.
Right?
But I don't want him finding out
so I can surprise him.
You're really set on that, huh?
I mean, it's his first birthday
since we started dating!
I want to make it so that Tani-kun
can never go back to average birthdays...
by giving him something
unforgettable.
Is that a curse?
That's terrifying.
YOU AND I ARE POLAR OPPOSITES
Happy Halloween!
(TANI'S BIRTHDAY EVE)
Thank you.
Tani-kun, you don't have cram school
or library duty tomorrow, right?
Right.
Then we have to walk together, okay?
Okay.
Yay!
It's a walking-home-from-school
birthday date!
What do I do?
I feel like she's going to
surprise me with something.
In my class in middle school...
Hinacchi! Happy birthday!
What? Thank you, everyone!
This makes me super happy!
It was tradition for everyone to
celebrate our classmates' birthdays,
because it'd be sad if someone's
birthday didn't get celebrated.
NOVEMBER
1ST
My turn came around, too, but...
TANI'S BIRTHDAY!
Tani-kun! Happy birthday!
Happy birthday!
QUIET...
Thank you.
Huh? Your reaction's kinda underwhelming.
*ACTUALLY GRATEFUL
I still don't know what
the right response was.
reactions
reactions that make
reactions that make people
reactions that make people happy
YAY
This is a problem.
I doubt that I can act surprised.
Taira, your reactions are so funny.
It makes all the goofing around worth it.
There!
And better luck next time!
All right!
No! Can it get any worse?
Ugh, I'm exhausted.
Taira-kun, there's something
I'd like to ask you.
Huh?
Are reactions something you work hard at?
Just what do you think I am, exactly?
Tani! We're up!
Oh! Was that about Suzuki's surprise?
Rain.
TAIRA'S
BIRTHDAY!
Whether it's raining or sunny,
it doesn't make a difference.
No one knows it's my birthday anyway.
Happy birthday to you!
Ayumi-chan! Happy birthday!
What? You did all this
after school just for me?
Happy birthday, dear Ayumi...
Oh, no! I'm so embarrassed!
Happy birthday to you!
That's mortifying!
For a second, I thought those guys
had set up a surprise for me!
Taira.
Your face looks kinda red.
What is it? Did you catch a cold?
No. It's nothing.
Yeah? That's fine, then.
Taira, where's your umbrella?
I have one, but it's not raining
hard enough to be worth opening.
Is that just how guys work?
That was thunder.
Let's hurry up and get back inside.
What is all this? Seriously!
How unlucky can I get today?
And on your birthday, too, huh, Taira?
You knew?
We asked each other
that in English class, right?
I just remembered.
We did?
You pronunciation of "October 10th"
was way better than it needed to be.
That last part was unnecessary.
Were you hoping
for an announcement at lunch?
Of course not!
I was joking!
Oh, right! I'll give you a present.
The sticker that came with
the bread I ate at lunch.
Huh? What's with the
"I don't want it" face?
It's just... my hands are dirty,
so I'll accept it from you later.
Thank you.
Oh! A yeti sticker!
That's pretty cute.
I wouldn't expect that from you.
Huh?
YOU...
Oh! Is that the one I gave you?
Taira, you're so conscientious!
Should I stay up until midnight?
TANI'S NIGHTS
END EARLY
If she does try to contact me, I don't
want it to seem like I ignored her.
No. Maybe I'm just being
too self-conscious again.
INCOMING CALL
SUZUKI MIYU
Hello?
Oh, great! You're still awake!
Or did my call wake you up?
I was awake.
No, with that voice,
you must've been sleeping.
Sorry! I'll hang up right after I say this,
so wait just a sec, okay?
Tani-kun, happy birthday.
Um, I actually wanted to give you
a more elaborate surprise,
but the simple truth is that I wanted to
be the first to wish you happy birthday.
Thank you.
But you were asleep. Sorry.
I wasn't asleep.
That's definitely a lie.
It isn't.
He sounds so sleepy.
Okay, good night! See you tomorrow.
I love you!
Just kidding!
Yeah.
Love you.
ASLEEP
ZZZ...
Morning, Tani-kun!
Happy birthday!
WOO-HOO
Huh? Tani-kun, today's your birthday?
Happy birthday.
Felicitations! Do you want a sticker?
Thank you.
Tani, here. Gummies.
BAM
Gummies. Thank you.
Tani.
THUNDER
CHOCOLATE
Thank you.
Well, I have to get to work.
He's hiding the fact that
he's embarrassed. That's so Taira!
Tani, word is that it's your birthday.
My, how old are you now?
The same age as us!
Oh, that reminds me...
POPURI
Oh! It's on-shift Taira!
It's you guys.
Don't go out of your way
to come here on your birthday!
The birthday-ing
is far from over, you know?
You're buying stuff, too?
Thank you.
Belated good wishes.
Huh?
Taira-kun, I didn't know
your birthday had already passed.
It's not right if I'm the only one
who gets a present.
What?
We heard from Azu earlier!
Honestly, Taira. Why the cold shoulder?
Happy birthday!
Please take it.
Well, shall we be off, Tani-kun?
Off to today's main event?
So I'm just a warm-up act?
Happy birthday!
What's this?
Taira-kun, did something nice happen?
I-It's nothing!
Ta-dah! A lighter and candles!
You're very prepared.
Whoops!
This might be just a little too much.
And now... we light them!
Somehow...
Tani-kun, I'm looking forward to knowing
the seventeen-year-old you.
Thank you.
This actually makes me really happy.
SHREWDLY, HAS HER OWN PORTION
It's so good!
Want to trade a bite?
Sure.
Tani-kun, here. Your birthday present.
A scarf.
It's still a little early, but...
If he can only wear it
with his regular clothes,
I'll have fewer chances to see it!
If you wore it, it would
make me super, super happy!
OVEREXCITED
Suzuki-san.
Wait. Is this...
THUD
time for a kiss?!
Thank you.
This makes me really happy.
Right.
What? It's not cold enough
to wear it yet, is it?
But since you gave it to me...
Oh! This weekend, let's go somewhere you
want to go and do something you want to do!
What I want to do?
We're always going where I want to go.
All right. I'll think about it.
Yay! I can't wait!
KISS...
Let's go somewhere you want to go
and do something you want to do!
What do I want to do?
The harder I think about it...
WHERE
I WANT
TO GO
WHAT
I WANT
TO DO
To be honest, anywhere is fine.
LACKS A DESIRE TO SIGHTSEE
Should I just go ahead and tell her that?
No.
Tani-kun, want to grab one with me?
Then I'll put the perfect plan together
and show you around!
I have one more self-centered request.
CUTESY...
Could it be that I...
am entirely too passive?
Natural...
History...
Museum!
This might be the first time since
my elementary school field trip!
Tani-kun, do you come here a lot?
No. I just remember liking it
when I was little.
Oh, you seem the type!
That's part of it, but...
MOVIE
TIME REQUIRED:
2 HOURS 30 MINUTES
There isn't anything good
playing right now.
ZOO
TIME REQUIRED:
2-3 HOURS
We went there before, though.
AQUARIUM
TIME REQUIRED:
1-2 HOURS
That seems a little short.
MUSEUM
TIME REQUIRED:
3-4 HOURS
After worrying and fretting,
this is the answer he arrived at!
SPECIAL
EXHIBIT
A
WORLD
OF
TREASURES
Want to see the special exhibit
while we're here?
Yeah, let's go! Let's go!
It seems pretty popular, too!
Huh?
I can't see anything at all!
Tani-kun, where are you?
Suzuki-san. Over here.
What?
MINUTES
LATER
All we could see were
the backs of people's heads.
I'm sorry.
What? Why? Tani-kun, you don't have
anything to apologize for.
We still haven't seen
the permanent exhibits!
Come on! Let's make the rounds!
Wow!
It's easy to see things
over here, isn't it?
The exhibition halls are really spacious.
Wow.
Is Emil's butterfly here?
THAT WAS
A MOTH
No, it's not.
It's so cute!
Its legs are adorable!
Whoa.
Wow!
There's so much stuff to see!
It's dark outside!
We got pretty far!
But we still didn't manage to get around
to everything. The museum is amazing!
That was fun!
WHEW
I'm hungry after all that. Want to grab
something to eat before we go home?
There seems to be a good
restaurant nearby. Let's go there.
What?! You researched in advance?!
Thank you!
TEMPORARILY
CLOSED
Sorry.
No, you had no control over this.
There's another restaurant nearby, so...
What? You really did a lot of research!
Oh...
With something like ramen,
the turnover is pretty fast, but...
What do you want to do? Should we line up?
WAIT
TIME
EATING
ARRIVE
HOME...
Let's go somewhere else.
Yeah.
From the looks of it,
it's over our budget.
SU
I'd love to go there when I grow up.
Oh! Suitable foodstuffs found!
It gets chilly once the sun
goes down, doesn't it?
I can feel that in my bones!
Somehow, I feel like none of
my plans went right today.
I WANT TO GO OVER THERE!
OVER
THERE
HMMM
TIME
SCHEDULE
Actually, have I been depending
on her too much?
Suzuki-san, are you tired
from all that walking?
I'm exhausted!
But because I walked so much,
this food is delicious!
It's a shame that we couldn't go
to the restaurant that you looked up,
but, in its own way,
this can't be beat. Right?
We're always doing
the things I want to do,
so today, I wanted to do
something that you wanted to do.
But I'm the one who ended up
having fun again today anyway.
I...
like it better when you're
having fun, Suzuki-san.
Huh?
Where we go, what we do...
More than those places or goals...
it's the time I spend with you,
Suzuki-san, that I enjoy.
I...
I totally get that!
What?
WHAT?
I'm the same!
I say stuff like, "I want to go there,"
or "I want to do this,"
but it's all really "I want to go
to XYZ with Tani-kun," you know?
It's the same! Just the same!
Huh? Um. Is it different?
No.
I'm the same, too.
Suzuki-san, thank you
for everything you do.
What? Where's this coming from?
What? That's what you were thinking?
I wish I could have done a better job
of showing you around.
It was all just fine, though!
But I appreciate that you feel that way.
You know... Today, I was all,
"Let's continue Tani-kun's birthday bash!"
But I made it so you had to be
considerate of my feelings instead.
"BASH"
MEANING
"HUGE
BIRTHDAY
PARTY"
Birthday bash?
No, I was the one
spinning in circles for no reason.
And the museum was fun.
Right?!
I want to go to that nearby
art museum sometime, too!
Yeah. Let's go.
I want to see all the colorful paintings!
I have some interest
in European art history.
I may be slightly lacking in
an intellectual spirit of inquiry.
No, I just have
no artistic sense at all, so...
Well, I'll see you at school.
Huh?
Good night.
Good night!
Squee!
I'm home!
My! You look like you had fun!